<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noah Virjee</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Noah Virjee</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 18:26:56 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blucardin.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prom_Seating</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/prom_seating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 18:26:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/prom_seating/</guid><description>An exercise in social networks, mathematical graphs, and community detection algorithms. Link to heading As I prepare to go to Prom, I find myself faced with the most challenging question of my high school career: Who will I sit with? From this initial question, we can derive a general problem: How do you optimally partition a given population people into tables of fixed size so that each person is seated around people who they like?</description></item><item><title>Christmas Lights Version 2</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/christmas-lights-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/christmas-lights-v2/</guid><description>This project is a continuation of my Christmas Lights project.
Overview Link to heading My Christmas tree lights project involved playing video on a set of addressable Christmas tree lights.
The program first determines the relative positions of the lights by turning on each light in sequence and using a camera to see where they are. This generates a list of coordinates which are stored on disk. Then for each frame of a video, the program resizes the frame to fit the light positions, then assigns each light the corresponding color at that point on the frame.</description></item><item><title>Wordle: What It Is, and How to Cheat</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/wordle-what-it-is-and-how-to-cheat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 02:03:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/wordle-what-it-is-and-how-to-cheat/</guid><description>I wrote an article for my school newspaper (The Franklin) that details my efforts to find the best wordle starting words using code-based analysis with probability and statistics.
Wordle: What It Is, and How to Cheat Link to heading Word games are not old, but there is a new one that has been taking the internet by storm: WORDLE! A web-based interactive game made by Josh Wardle that was recently bought by the New York Times for seven-figures.</description></item><item><title>A Question a Day</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/a-question-a-day/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 02:03:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/a-question-a-day/</guid><description>I have a lot of questions, so I decided to put them to good use on the internet.
I programmed a twitter bot to post a question of mine everyday. It did not gain much traction on the internet, but was good practice in using APIs.
Twitter account: https://twitter.com/aquestionaday_
Here is the code:</description></item><item><title>Candy Canes</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/candy-canes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 02:03:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/candy-canes/</guid><description>My school has an annual candy cane sale where any student can buy a candy cane for any other student.
One day, I had some spare time after school and went to help with the packaging of candy canes. What I saw shocked me. Due to the pandemic, candy canes had moved to online google form registration, away from physical handwritten notes. The poor organizer was manually copy-pasting information from the google form submissions into canva to be printed!</description></item><item><title>CCC Certificate of Distinction</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/ccc-certificate-of-distinction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 02:03:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/ccc-certificate-of-distinction/</guid><description>I was in TDSB Virtual Secondary School (VSS) for grade 9. Needless to say, I got quite bored, so I decided to join the VSS Computer Club.
The VSS Computer Club was a bunch of computer enthusiasts that hosted weekly computing discussion meetings and code golf competitions. As part of the computer club, I was given the opportunity to write the Canadian Computing Competition (CCC) hosted by the University of Waterloo.</description></item><item><title>Missile Guidance Systems</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/missile-guidance-systems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 02:03:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/missile-guidance-systems/</guid><description>I had to make a presentation on the impacts of computers on society for a computer science course. I chose to talk about missile guidance systems.</description></item><item><title>ERS Dashboard</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/ers-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/ers-dashboard/</guid><description>A business partner asked my father for assistance in creating a dashboard system for his online business. The company provides tests to job agencies that they can give to their clients to determine if the client is ready to enter the workforce or to indicate areas that need improvement (https://ersscale.com/). My father asked my opinion after realizing that the commercial solution (Power BI by Microsoft) was too expensive and inflexible. After some investagation, I created a website that would solve the problem.</description></item><item><title>Cartoonify</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cartoonify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cartoonify/</guid><description>All code can be found here: https://github.com/blucardin/cartoonify
Explanation video can be found here: https://youtu.be/S3cUFmjqQ-U
I submit this project as the final project of CS50p.
Cartoonify is a Python console application that can take an image or video file as input and produce a cartoonified version of it. The cartoonification process involves reducing the color depth of the image, detecting edges in the image, and overlaying the simplified colors and edges to create a cartoon effect.</description></item><item><title>Chrsistmas Lights</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/chrsistmas-lights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/chrsistmas-lights/</guid><description>All code can be found here: https://github.com/blucardin/Lights-
Explanation video can be found here: https://youtu.be/PH5mAJPhH-c
I submit this project as the final project of CS50x.
In this project, I displayed videos and images on an addressable set of Christmas lights. I used a raspberry pi running python to control the lights. It would accept a numpy array of frames from my computer over ssh. Each frame would be a 2d array of RGB values which the pi would then encode and send to the lights over serial.</description></item><item><title>CS50p</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cs50p/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cs50p/</guid><description>To expand my problem-solving capabilities as a programmer, I decided to take the CS50p online course and master the python programming language. CS50p is Harvard University’s introduction to programming with Python. Students learn about functions, arguments, and return values; variables and types; conditionals and Boolean expressions; and loops. They also learn how to handle exceptions, find and fix bugs, and write unit tests; use third-party libraries; validate and extract data with regular expressions; model real-world entities with classes, objects, methods, and properties; and read and write files.</description></item><item><title>CS50x</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cs50x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/cs50x/</guid><description>To learn more about computer science and expand my capabilities as a programmer, I decided to take the CS50x online course. CS50x is Harvard University’s introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science. It teaches you how to solve problems, both with and without code, with an emphasis on correctness, design, and style. Topics include computational thinking, abstraction, algorithms, data structures, and computer science more generally. Problem sets inspired by the arts, humanities, social sciences, and sciences.</description></item><item><title>Website Snake</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/website-snake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/website-snake/</guid><description>I did a hackathon (programming marathon) where I created an online snake video game by myself. I wanted to test my abilities and I ended up having a lot of fun.
Users were able to play the snake game, then, once they died, add their score and name to a global leaderboard stored in a CockroachDB database.
I will be honest, for this side project I stayed up for 36 hours straight coding and was a little loopy when doing the project description and video.</description></item><item><title>Video to Ascii Art</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/video-to-ascii-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/video-to-ascii-art/</guid><description>I was bored one weekend so I decided to create some code to convert videos to ascii art. Everyone in my ICS class was trying to get slightly higher marks by including ascii gifs in their console projects and I wanted to show off a bit.
I used python with the pillow image library to read in video/image files, convert each frame to ascii art, and stitch everything back together. The final code was quite simple but worked really well.</description></item><item><title>Coinspire</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/coinspire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/coinspire/</guid><description>Two of my close friends and I decided to do a hackathon one weekend. We signed up for TOHacks 2022 (https://www.tohacks.ca/) and spent the next 24 hours together building a web-based application.
We built Coinspire, a collaborative place where users from around the world can contribute pixel by pixel to collaboratively create a graphical image!
On the coinspire website, users can place one pixel on a large 1000 by 1000 grid once every second.</description></item><item><title>Fractals</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/fractals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/fractals/</guid><description>At my school, we have a specialized Wednesday program where students can attend educational sessions outside of school.
For one Wednesday session, I chose to attend a mini-course on fractals. Unfortunately, I was put online at this time (due to the pandemic) and was unable to participate in the physical fractal building activities.
So, I decided to code fractals instead. I wrote python scripts to generate different kinds of fractals using python’s turtle module.</description></item><item><title>Contact me</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 22:56:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/contact/</guid><description>LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/noah-virjee-939029193/
GitHub: https://github.com/blucardin
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/noahvirjee31/
Devpost: https://devpost.com/noah-virjee</description></item><item><title>Hi there, I'm Noah 👋</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 22:48:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a grade 12 high school student aspiring developer in Toronto, Canada. I like helping people, solving problems, and doing cool things.
My best projects so far are a video display made of addressable Christmas Lights and an analytics dashboard.
I also have done some fractal stuff if you want something cool to look at.
I mostly work in python, but I also know Javascipt (for web development), java (for school), and C (when I want to confuse myself).</description></item><item><title>Esocentric Laguage Interpreter</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/esocentric-laguage-interpreter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/esocentric-laguage-interpreter/</guid><description>I wanted to try my hand at writing an interpreter for a programming language. After conducting some research, I found a simple language called “Brainfuck” that emulated a turing machine using only 8 distinct commands.
I wrote the code on the weekend and enjoyed the project. It was surprisingly challenging.
Learn more about Brainfuck here: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brainfuck All code can be found here: https://github.com/blucardin/Brainf_ck-Interpreter</description></item><item><title>Dicerning</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/dicerning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/dicerning/</guid><description>I was in TDSB Virtual Secondary School (VSS) for grade 9. Needless to say, I got quite bored, so I decided to join the VSS Computer Club.
The VSS Computer Club was a bunch of computer enthusiasts that hosted weekly computing discussion meetings and code golf competitions. At the end of the year, the club put together a hackathon (a 48 hour event where programmers compete in teams to build the best computer project).</description></item><item><title>Snake</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/snake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/projects/snake/</guid><description>When I was in grade 8, I wanted to make a snake game. So for a few months I worked really hard and developed a classic game of snake in python using pygame.
All code can be found here: https://github.com/blucardin/snake
Play the game on repl.it: https://replit.com/join/mwceiktv-noahvirjee</description></item><item><title>My Website!</title><link>https://blucardin.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blucardin.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello World! Link to heading I just created a personal website for myself. This is not the first website I have created (nor is it the last), but I am still quite proud of it.
My motivation Link to heading There are three main reasons why I created this website:
I am a relatively young computer enthusiast and I need to prove that I know how to do computer stuff without actually doing too much computer stuff.</description></item></channel></rss>